<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Maximuming At The Peak</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Maximuming At The Peak</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Expand Grids with...`expand.grid()`</title>
      <link>/2018/02/28/expand-grids-with-expand-grid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/28/expand-grids-with-expand-grid/</guid>
      <description>COPY / PASTE HERE:   expand.grid(seq(0,10), seq(0,10), seq(0,10))
 Another quick one but useful. I recently had a use-case at work where I was plotting datapoints of events on a 2d canvas. We had thousands of clients and a unique canvas where I needed to paint thousands of events for each client. I decided to normalize everything to a 0-100 scale across the x and y dimensions. The problem which prompted me to use expand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grouped Summary With `tapply()`</title>
      <link>/2018/02/23/grouped-summary-with-purrr-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/23/grouped-summary-with-purrr-map/</guid>
      <description>COPY / PASTE HERE:   mtcars %&amp;gt;% split(.$cyl) %&amp;gt;% map(summary)
 This is a quick one and sourced from this SO answer but I kept googling it so wanted to just put it up here.
require(dplyr) require(purrr) mtcars %&amp;gt;% split(.$cyl) %&amp;gt;% map(summary) ## $`4` ## mpg cyl disp hp ## Min. :21.40 Min. :4 Min. : 71.10 Min. : 52.00 ## 1st Qu.:22.80 1st Qu.:4 1st Qu.: 78.85 1st Qu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logarithmic Bucketing in R</title>
      <link>/2017/12/07/logarithmic-bucketing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/12/07/logarithmic-bucketing/</guid>
      <description>COPY / PASTE HERE:   c(0,10^(1:7))
  paste0(‘&amp;lt;=’,scales::comma(c(10^(1:7))))
 Some of the datasets I deal with are lognormally distributed. Basically what this means is they follow the 80/20 rule where 80% of the sum of the values comes from the top 20% of the observations when sorted descending. There are a lot of observations with very low values relative to the range. Often I bucket things into bins for reporting based on log base-10 rule where we bucket “observations less than 10”, then observations less than 100 then 1,000 then 10,000 etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plot Grouped Indexed Time-Series Changes</title>
      <link>/2017/12/05/indexed-time-series-changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/12/05/indexed-time-series-changes/</guid>
      <description>COPY / PASTE HERE:   mutate( index = value / value[1] - 1 )
 One thing I do at my job all. the. time is index time-series together in order to compare relative changes in a given time window. The problem statement is usually when I’m comparing the price changes of two assets with vastly different prices. So trying to plot something moving from $1MM to $1.1MM on the same plot as something moving from $10 to $11.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Train Schedule</title>
      <link>/2017/10/01/the-train-schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/10/01/the-train-schedule/</guid>
      <description>This website needs content. I don’t really know what to write at the moment so I’m going to just start with a simple recreation of a famous old ( originally made 137 years ago) visualization to get things rolling. I could have chosen to write about Napoleon’s infamous march but plenty of people wrote about that already.
I recently purchased a copy of https://www.amazon.co.uk/Visual-Display-Quantitative-Information/dp/0961392142 by Edward Tufte. The cover image is a photo of E.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Troy. I am a data analyst based in London. Everything I write here represents my own thought and opinions.
What does Peak Maximum mean? Not sure, one of my friends said something about taking something to the Peak Maximum and I thought it was funny and the domain name was available for $5.00 and I needed something to do.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>